<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Nerdery | Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/categories/nerdery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-21T08:50:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Dodds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Shared Calendar for Political Elections]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2014/01/04/a-shared-calendar-for-political-elections/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-04T10:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2014/01/04/a-shared-calendar-for-political-elections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been taking dedicated time to think through different areas of my life—family, finances, spirtuality, etc. One area where I&rsquo;m much less proactive than I&rsquo;d like to admit is civic duty (a fancy way of saying I don&rsquo;t research my representatives or prepare for elections well).</p>

<p>Many people my age (late 20s) are burned out on politics in general. The flow of constant, extreme polarization wears me out too.</p>

<p>Frustrated or not, though, I live in a country where I can make my voice heard at the polls, and that&rsquo;s an incredible privilige. I&rsquo;d be remiss not to take advantage of it.</p>

<p>So, this year I decided to start by plotting out election dates on a calendar. There aren&rsquo;t many, but knowing they&rsquo;re on the horizen will help me do research and prepare to cast a vote.</p>

<p>Interestingly, or maybe not, I struggled to find a well-done calendar of those dates (let me know if this resource exists). What I <em>really</em> wanted was an iCal or XML URL I could add to my calendar automatically.</p>

<p>Even though there are only a handful of dates this year, I went ahead and added them to Google Calendar and made it public. I&rsquo;ll keep this updated for SC General Elections as well as Greenville, SC County elections and Greenville, SC Municipal Elections.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the calendar in&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/ical/unaunjc6lsf3e2ddqktmmcm4k4%40group.calendar.google.com/public/basic.ics">iCal format</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/feeds/unaunjc6lsf3e2ddqktmmcm4k4%40group.calendar.google.com/public/basic">XML format</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=unaunjc6lsf3e2ddqktmmcm4k4%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;ctz=America/New_York">HTML link</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Hopefully this will help others like me keep better tabs on elections and who is representing me in Washington, South Carolina and Greenville.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Music of Western North Carolina]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2013/12/21/the-music-of-western-north-carolina/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-21T13:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2013/12/21/the-music-of-western-north-carolina</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m not much a radio listener, but there&rsquo;s one station we get in Upstate South Carolina that makes me smile every time I tune in.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Most of the time they play mountain music—bluegrass, authentic country and Americana. A fair number of songs they play come straight from the heart of the Appalachian region that the radio waves cover.</p>

<p>There are other types of music I listen to more often, but there&rsquo;s something about mountain music that&rsquo;s hard to describe. It feels deep-rooted and full of story.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago I ran across a quote in a magazine that described it beautifully:</p>

<blockquote><p>It&rsquo;s found where the distance between saint and sinner is no further than the space between frets, where backsliders and Baptists sit together, right up on one another, listening to a mandolin that sounds like angels dancing on the rim of a Mason jar.It&rsquo;s wound around the country lyrics of a story song, of folks leaving town on a ghost train or the wings of a dove. And it lives in the wail of the bastard child called rock and roll, whose family tree branches into juke joints and smoke-filled bars,its roots prying up the floorboards of front porches and barn dances. <br><br>The music that lives in Western North Carolina, either by birth or divine guidance, is as good at it is varied. The sound comes form the instruments, but the music comes fromthe souls of the boys pulling the strings. It rolls down the mountains and through the hills and and takes hold before the soil turns to sand, remaining on the solid ground it knows well. Let others shag on boardwalks. We pound boots on quartz and clay,nodding our heads in time and agreement. So it has been and so it shall be, forever and always. Amen.<br><br>—Shari Smith</p></blockquote>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The name of the radio station is WNCW, and you can <a href="http://wncw.org/listen-live">listen live on their website</a>. <a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Sky by Morning]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2013/12/20/red-sky-by-morning/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-20T13:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2013/12/20/red-sky-by-morning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The sky outside my kitchen window this morning was a brilliant pinkish red. As I grabbed a pair of shoes so I could enjoy the view outside, I remembered a phrase I&rsquo;d heard many times before:</p>

<p> <strong>&ldquo;Red sky by night, sailors delight. Red sky by morning, sailors take warning.&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p> I checked the forecast later, and sure enough, rain was on the way. I decided to look at the science behind the saying to see if the adage was a reliable meteoralogical predictor.</p>

<p> The atmospheric specifics can get a bit heady, but the phrase actually proves true in a certain cross section of the planet. Here&rsquo;s a simple explanation from Wikipedia:</p>

<blockquote><p>The rhyme is a rule of thumb for weather forecasting, dating back over 2,000 years, based on the reddish glow of the morning or evening sky, caused by haze or clouds related to storms in the region. Due to the rotation of the Earth, storm systems travel from west to east in the mid-latitudes. A reddish sunrise, caused by particles suspended in the air, often foreshadows an approaching storm, which will be arriving from the West, within the day. Conversely, a reddish sunset often indicates that a storm system is on the west side (same side as the sunset), travelling away from the viewer.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p></blockquote>

<p> But, it turns out this is only true for latitudes where wind currents move westward (westerlies). Those regions are towards the top and bottom of the earth. In the middle of the planet, where the easterly trade winds blow, the effect is opposite.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p> <img src="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/images/blog/2013/12/global-winds.jpg"></p>

<p> So, here in South Carolina, it&rsquo;s going to be a rainy weekend.</p>

<p> <em>Related nerdy stuff:</em></p>

<p> The phrase has been used throughout history. Shakespeare used it in his poem <em>Venus and Andronis</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>“Like a red morn that ever yet betokened,<br>
 Wreck to the seaman, tempest to the field,<br>
 Sorrow to the shepherds, woe unto the birds,<br>
 Gusts and foul flaws to herdmen and to herds.”<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p></blockquote>

<p> Jesus used the phrase in the Bible, quoted in Matthew 16:2-3:</p>

<blockquote><p>He answered them, “When it is evening, you say, ‘It will be fair weather, for the sky is red.’ And in the morning, ‘It will be stormy today, for the sky is red and threatening.’ You know how to interpret the appearance of the sky, but you cannot interpret the signs of the times.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p></blockquote>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Read the [full Wikipedia article, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_sky_at_morning">&ldquo;Red sky at morning&rdquo;</a>. <a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Dig into the nitty gritty of atmospheric particles and more <a href="http://www.esrl.noaa.gov/gmd/grad/about/redsky/">on the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&rsquo;s site</a>.   <a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>You can read the entire poem, Venus and Andronis, <a href="http://shakespeare.mit.edu/Poetry/VenusAndAdonis.html">on MIT&rsquo;s website</a>. <a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Check out <a href="http://www.esvbible.org/Matthew+16/">the entire chapter of Matthew 16</a>. <a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gather and move nested audio files via command line]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2013/08/22/gather-and-move-nested-files-via-command-line/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T15:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2013/08/22/gather-and-move-nested-files-via-command-line</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the years my brother has amassed a large music library of 20,000+ songs. He has a great taste for sound, but when it comes to technology his nerd DNA is dwarfed by his <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693251917/">outdoorsman DNA</a>. After several computer upgrades, multiple iTunes Library restorations and transfers, and no file file management whatsoever, a significant portion of his audio files were corrupt and wouldn&rsquo;t play (via iTunes or in the Finder on his Mac). Music is a very important part of his life, so I set out to help him.</p>

<p>After tinkering for a bit I discovered that running bad files through an mp3 converter fixed the problem—the content was intact, but iTunes was having trouble reading them fully<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Having discovered the fix for individual files, I faced another problem: those items were spread across a directory with thousands of nested folders, some several levels deep in the hierarchy. There was no way I was going to manually move 20,000 files.</p>

<p><img src="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/images/blog/2013/08/nested-audio-files-1.png" alt="Screenshot of nested audio files several folders deep" style="border: 1px solid gray"></p>

<p>My first crack at automating the process was finding an mp3 conversion tool that would search through folders, find files, and convert them in place. <a href="http://www.nch.com.au/switch/index.html">Switch</a> seemed like it would do the job initially, but after several failed attempts I figured that some combination of names in the file path was breaking the process. I tried a few more programs unsuccessfully before remembering that I had no need to preserve the existing order as iTunes automatically generates an artist/album/song folder structure when you import new files.</p>

<p>After that, I turned to the terminal to see if I could efficiently gather all of the files into a single clean directory. (Scared of the terminal? Don&rsquo;t be<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.)</p>

<p>Exploring regex commands<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> seemed promising<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> until I realized that I needed to move multiple file types. Frustration drove me to enlist my business partner (and hacker extraordinaire) <a href="http://twitter.com/masondesu">Mason Stewart&rsquo;s</a> help.</p>

<p>We discovered that using a unix find command, file name specification, and move command for each individual file type worked like a charm.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>//Use this command to find and move a specific kind of file in a directory.
</span><span class='line'>//This command searches recursively through nested folders.&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>$ find ~/old-music-folder -name &lsquo;*.mp3&rsquo; -exec mv {} ~/new-music-folder \;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><em><a href="https://gist.github.com/ericdodds/6306638.js">Here&rsquo;s a link to the gist on GitHub.</a></em></p>

<p>The result: all of the audio files in a single folder, easily digestible by the mp3 converter.</p>

<p><img src="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/images/blog/2013/08/nested-audio-files-2.png" alt="Screenshot of nested audio files moved to a single directory" style="border: 1px solid gray"></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>More specifically, iTunes recognized the presence of a corrupt file in the library, but couldn&rsquo;t actually play it and would skip to the next song. <a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Even if you&rsquo;re not nerdy by nature, knowing a few basic unix commands is super powerful. For example, find the Terminal (or command line app) on your computer and type &ldquo;whois ericdodds.com&rdquo;. <a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Mason showed me <a href="http://leaverou.github.io/regexplained/">this amazing regex playground</a> by <a href="http://lea.verou.me/">Lea Verou</a>. I still understand very little about regex, but the taste I had showed me that it&rsquo;s an incredibly powerful tool.<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>&ldquo;Some people, when confronted with a problem, think &lsquo;I know, I&rsquo;ll use regular expressions.&rsquo; Now they have two problems. —Jamie Zawinski&rdquo;<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
