<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-19T13:53:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Few Spring Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/05/08/a-few-spring-photos-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-08T17:38:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/05/08/a-few-spring-photos-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We went to see the circus. The theme song was maddeningly repetitive, but the tightrope walkers made up for it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8694366898/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8395/8694366898_2f6f95360a_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-01 February mobile photos 03" /></a></p>

<p>Mike and Jeff&rsquo;s is a local pulled pork-favorite.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8694367146/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8257/8694367146_79f6a3633a_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-05 February mobile photos 04" /></a></p>

<p>Token moody mobile photo.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693249151/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8119/8693249151_8708b6bc51_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-20 February mobile photos 07" /></a></p>

<p>I traveled to San Francisco on business, and my wife came along to make a work-cation of it. The trees in the Music Concourse Community area of Golden Gate Park are very crustaceous.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693250513/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8542/8693250513_501523768c_c.jpg" alt="2013-03-03 March mobile photos 09" /></a></p>

<p>A lone onlooker at the Pacific Ocean.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693250665/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8121/8693250665_76a4ee7ffc_c.jpg" alt="2013-03-03 March mobile photos 11" /></a></p>

<p>If you haven&rsquo;t visited, the history lessons from Alcatraz (and the US prison system in general) are fascinating. Everyone loves a harrowing escape story.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693250863/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8262/8693250863_bfcb3f6d1d_c.jpg" alt="2013-03-04 March mobile photos 13" /></a></p>

<p>What would Bill Murray do? A very valid question in the heart of the Mission District.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8694369306/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8396/8694369306_4461be6f2b_c.jpg" alt="2013-03-04 March mobile photos 17" /></a></p>

<p>I happened upon free Carrie Underwood box seats, so I took my wife on a date. Not my favorite music, but the show was amazing entertainment, and Carrie has some serious pipes.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693251405/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8546/8693251405_1cc12afe5a_c.jpg" alt="2013-04-16 April mobile photos 05" /></a></p>

<p>I finally conquered my first multi-pitch climb. This is a shot of my brother scaling the second section.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693251651/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8120/8693251651_777d3cfc72_c.jpg" alt="2013-04-21 April mobile photos 06" /></a></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a large flat spot on Looking Glass Rock that climbers call the &ldquo;Parking Lot.&rdquo; It makes for a great rest halfway up.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8693251917/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8693251917_0f38e349f5_c.jpg" alt="2013-04-21 April mobile photos 09" /></a></p>

<p>My lovely wife, basking in the glow of a bonfire.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8694370406/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8118/8694370406_6b979ce058_c.jpg" alt="2013-04-26 April mobile photos 11" /></a></p>

<p>We had a healthy does of April showers this spring.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8694373918/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8121/8694373918_0edaf11e44_c.jpg" alt="2013-03-29 March mobile photos 01" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailbox App and the Illusion of Moving Information]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/mailbox-app-and-the-illusion-of-moving-information/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T14:50:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/mailbox-app-and-the-illusion-of-moving-information</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently downloaded the much anticipated Mailbox app. It&rsquo;s a fine tool, designed well, with a pretty slick interface. Arguably, the most exciting feature of the product is it&rsquo;s ability to &lsquo;snooze&rsquo; messages and bring them back at various intervals. Selling the idea of an easily attainable inbox zero made a lot of people salivate.</p>

<p><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_0870-e1362685058726.jpg" alt="IMG_0870" /></p>

<p>Hopefully the app helps people, but I don&rsquo;t think it will solve one of the real problems (especially for teams) that we have with email, which is the tendency to use it as a to-do list &ndash; the <a href="http://mailboxapp.com/story">primary reason creators gave</a> for building the app.</p>

<p>People are hungry for help because of the volume of email they receive. The medium has grown from an efficient person-to-person communication tool to a firehose of unrelated information from any and every possible source (including physical devices). Lots of that information needs to be acted on, not just consumed. Figuring out how to deal with the constant stream can be a tall task.</p>

<p>Dealing with information and moving it around are two different things, though. Snoozing an email for a week is great, until you&rsquo;ve snoozed it every week for a month straight. At that point you&rsquo;ve given yourself a pat on the back for cleaning your inbox, when all you&rsquo;ve done is temporarily hidden something you need to do.</p>

<p>Feeling good about hiding an email you need to act on is the same as feeling good about neatly labeling and filing past-due bills you need to pay.</p>

<p>Tools like Mailbox do a great job of helping you move things around in a logical, efficient way. That&rsquo;s great for individuals who use email mostly on their mobile devices, but it&rsquo;s a far cry from <a href="http://visualidiot.com/articles/mailappapp">revolutionizing the tool itself</a>, especially for teams working on complex projects.</p>

<p><del>The opportunity is so much larger than improving the moving process. We need tools that remove the manual labor associated with translating that information into the actions that move strategies forward and produce products and services. Right now that process is clunky, and the pain is magnified on mobile devices.</del></p>

<p><del>Apps that allow creation of to-do&rsquo;s via email are a step in the right direction, but still require some manual labor and processing. <a href="http://www.taskforceapp.com/">Taskforce</a> is an interesting solution, but keeps email in the browser, and seems much less robust than Asana or Trello. (I&rsquo;d love to hear about other solutions I haven&rsquo;t come across.)</del></p>

<p>UPDATE:</p>

<p>Of course, this is the internet, and everything exists. Both <a href="http://do.com">do.com</a> and <a href="http://www.producteev.com/">Producteev</a> provide pretty slick Gmail gadgets that allow you to turn emails into tasks.</p>

<p>The more I&rsquo;ve heard people talk about the Mailbox app, the more I&rsquo;ve noticed complaints that &ldquo;it screwed up Gmail on my computer.&rdquo; The aggravated users are referring to labels, and the specific way in which Mailbox uses them to categorize messages. Even though there was an explanation in the onboarding process, I&rsquo;ve run across a surprising number of people who deleted the app because the user flow didn&rsquo;t translate well between mobile and desktop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Few Winter Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/02/23/a-few-winter-photos/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-23T10:55:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/02/23/a-few-winter-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I carved out a few hours on a rainy morning to collect pictures from the last few months. It&rsquo;s been a good winter.</p>

<hr />

<p>We had a birthday backyard camping adventure with my nephew in December. He lasted the whole night outside in 30º weather.</p>

<p> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8462968640/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8531/8462968640_36f284ec03_c.jpg" alt="2012-12-13 Rush's birthday camping 06" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8461871299/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8110/8461871299_d394076444_c.jpg" alt="2012-12-13 Rush's birthday camping 10" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p>Julie&rsquo;s uncle is a cowboy from the west.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8462976608/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8370/8462976608_fba892ef37_c.jpg" alt="2012-12-25 Curt Pippenger 02" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p>Window in a small, rural Southern church.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8463053736/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8227/8463053736_78a05cf6ce_c.jpg" alt="2012-12-25 Christmas day 01" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p>A very rainy mountain biking excursion.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8463074094/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8089/8463074094_5798f42347_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-12 Mountain biking 02" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8461979833/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8391/8461979833_19ab5b309a_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-12 Mountain biking 10" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8463082028/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8392/8463082028_c3c77648d9_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-12 Mountain biking 13" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8461983315/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8506/8461983315_bd9e501abe_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-12 Mountain biking 17" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p>Weather broke in January and my brother took us north for a climbing lesson.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500800864/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8516/8500800864_06c3a854e5_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-21 Climbing at the Cereal Wall 07" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500801170/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8252/8500801170_9816420f87_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-21 Climbing at the Cereal Wall 08" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8499695479/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8235/8499695479_8471551140_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-21 Climbing at the Cereal Wall 10" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p>Mobile photos.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500813010/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8516/8500813010_32484dd123_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-05 January mobile photos 04" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8499706705/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8383/8499706705_5805502b8f_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-05 January mobile photos 07" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8499707003/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8512/8499707003_abe7bf16c2_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-05 January mobile photos 08" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8499707155/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8232/8499707155_7604580e2e_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-23 January mobile photos 19" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500813788/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8085/8500813788_ecdc7f5eb8_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-25 January mobile photos 16" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500814030/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8532/8500814030_00c6e6e777_c.jpg" alt="2013-01-29 January mobile photos 17" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p>This was quite possibly the coldest adventure of my life. 20+ mile-per-hour winds and 20º weather made for painful and slow climbing, but we had a great time anyways.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8499753313/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8391/8499753313_cf758966dd_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-17 Climbing at Looking Glass Rock 13" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500859954/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8249/8500859954_60cd9cc9a6_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-17 Climbing at Looking Glass Rock 14" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8500860202/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8245/8500860202_1ddddd7907_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-17 Climbing at Looking Glass Rock 16" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8499754195/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8110/8499754195_3b55b30c73_c.jpg" alt="2013-02-17 Climbing at Looking Glass Rock 11" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Differences in Distance at My New Work Space]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/01/04/three-differences-in-distance-at-my-new-work-space/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T12:59:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/01/04/three-differences-in-distance-at-my-new-work-space</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>1) Distance from home</h4>

<p>My old job was about .6 miles from my house. I biked to work most days, and often told my wife that I was trying to enjoy a rare proximity to the office that I might not experience again. And then I went to work at The Iron Yard, and my <em>commute became even shorter</em>.</p>

<p>To get from my front door to my desk takes approximately 5 and a half minutes on foot, or 755 steps, at a leisurely pace. It&rsquo;s so great that I almost feel bad telling you about it. Almost.</p>

<h4>2) Distance to the water closet</h4>

<p>This is petty, but the bathroom is a lot closer than it used to be. It&rsquo;s convenient. I drink a lot of water. Sue me.</p>

<h4>3) Distance to coffee</h4>

<p>Some people might argue that being close to coffee in the morning is a basic human right, but those people probably aren&rsquo;t human until they&rsquo;ve had their coffee, so it doesn&rsquo;t matter. I really like coffee, and I have to walk almost 3 times further to get to it in the new office. That means I drink less of it, which means my teeth won&rsquo;t brown as quickly as I age. Inconvenient, but a win.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Love is in the...Chinese Tech Company Culture? ]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/14/love-is-in-the-chinese-tech-company-culture/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T13:27:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/14/love-is-in-the-chinese-tech-company-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Company culture is incredibly important, and leaders have been known to allow very non-traditional activity to foster it. In China, one of those activities is encouraging love – the romantic kind – between their <em>employees</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Fast Company reports</strong> on Alibaba&rsquo;s annual mass weddings performed by their CEO:</p>

<blockquote><p>But Song was not the only woman wearing white at her wedding. In fact, she wasn&rsquo;t even the only bride. There were 324 others, all participating in a marriage ceremony led by Alibaba CEO Jack Ma, who performs a mass wedding for his employees every May. Song particularly remembers one thing Ma told the brides and grooms: &ldquo;Love is not something you say. It&rsquo;s something you do&mdash;starting tonight!&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><em><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1802729/leaders-alibaba-youku-and-baidu-are-slowly-shaking-chinas-corporate-culture">Read the full article here.</a></em></p>

<p><strong>A cloud computing company in Chengdu, China</strong> awards &ldquo;Love Bonuses&rdquo; to workers who fall in love:</p>

<blockquote><p>In China’s own Silicon Valley in Sichuan Province, the Chengdu cloud computing company has decided to reward its employees for falling in love, reports the People’s Daily.</p></blockquote>

<p>Chengdu executives told the People’s Daily, that they came up with the idea after seeing the emotional turmoil of his young workers, awarding a financial bonus for workers willing to tuoguang – “strip” – slang for saying goodbye to the single life. The company hopes that if their employees fall in love with their colleagues, they will “have an even more harmonious team”&hellip;</p>

<p><em><a href="http://worldcrunch.com/culture-society/chinese-tech-firm-gives-employees-quot-love-bonus-quot-to-hook-up/china-chengdu-it-workers-love-single/c3s10178/#.UKubo6WmC-L">Read the full article here.</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I've Been Up To at the New Gig]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/what-ive-been-up-to-at-the-new-gig/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T16:47:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/what-ive-been-up-to-at-the-new-gig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last month has been a bit wild, what with <a href="http://ericdodds.com/follow-your-procrastination/">diving into a new industry</a> and all. Here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve been up to:</p>

<p>—Building a workflow and project management system that works for our team.
<em>We&rsquo;ve tried app after app, but the current system of <a href="https://trello.com">Trello</a> + <a href="https://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> + <a href="%22https://dispatch.io">Dispatch</a> + <a href="%22http://voxer.com">Voxer</a> seems to get the job done. Coming from a place where process was inflexible, working with a small team who&rsquo;s willing to change has been delightful.</em></p>

<p>—Organizing <em>everything</em>
<em>File here, file there, file, file everywhere! Grunt work, but important grunt work. I&rsquo;m almost obsessive-compulsive about file structure and organization, and being able to build a clean and flexible structure from the beginning makes life oh-so-much easier.</em></p>

<p>—Setting up bank accounts, payroll, and health benefits</p>

<p>—Planning up-fit for two separate office locations, including layout and broad design
<em>Including designing a very cost-effective desk design using black pipe and fittings (like <a href="http://theironyard.com/2012/11/its-time-to-take-a-stand-cowork-standing-desks/">this</a>, but cheaper)</em></p>

<p>—Researching investors and startups in the Southeast</p>

<p>—Attending the <a href="http://theironyard.com/2012/11/what-the-iron-yard-learned-at-the-gan-founders-conference/">GAN Founders Conference</a> in Boston (and eating some really good food while I was there)</p>

<p>—Writing (for <a href="http://www.gsabusiness.com">GSA Business</a> and <a href="http://theironyard.com/blog/">The Iron Yard</a>)</p>

<p>—Dreaming with the <a href="http://coderdojogreenville.com">CoderDojo crew</a> about teaching people more people to code</p>

<p>—Laying the groundwork for <a href="http://grok.cc">Grok 2013</a></p>

<p>—Re-branding The Iron Yard (coming soon to an internet near you)
<em>I had the chance to work with <a href="http://twitter.com/whale">Matthew Smith</a> and <a href="http://dribbble.com/justinhall">Justin Hall</a> to on the logo and visual elements (more on that soon), and I worked with Peter Barth to craft our positioning (more on that soon, too).</em></p>

<p>—Building a content strategy, marketing, and PR plan for The Iron Yard</p>

<p>—Reading a good amount of tech news</p>

<p>—Brainstorming with the <a href="http://ridepost.com">RidePost</a> crew about copy and user experience for a new feature</p>

<p>—Talking and writing with <a href="http://danwaldschmidt.com">Dan Waldschmidt</a> on his new project</p>

<p>—<a href="http://daytum.com/displays/274600">Walking a lot</a>.</p>

<p>I work harder and come home happier than I ever have before.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Update on the Hungry Peddler]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/11/19/an-update-on-the-hungry-peddler/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T10:50:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/11/19/an-update-on-the-hungry-peddler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several months ago I <a href="http://ericdodds.com/pay-attention-when-the-peddler-is-hungry/">wrote about</a> Autodesk laying off 500 employees. An experience I had with one of their subsidiaries prior to the downsizing made wonder if I should&rsquo;ve sensed trouble, but it turns out my (admittedly) uninformed speculation was off base. From a <a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2012/09/ff-autodesk-and-the-big-make/">recent Wired feature</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>On paper, no firm is better positioned to take advantage of a maker-led future than Autodesk, whose 30 years of experience in <a href="http://usa.autodesk.com/adsk/servlet/item?siteID=123112&amp;id=17690382">computer-aided design</a> give it unparalleled intelligence about the capabilities that designers want and need in their software. Despite some recent financial travails (in August, <a href="http://investors.autodesk.com/phoenix.zhtml?c=117861&amp;p=irol-irhome">lower-than-expected earnings</a> forced the layoff of some 500 employees), Autodesk’s core professional business affords it enviable leeway to pursue the consumer market without jeopardizing its solvency.</p></blockquote>

<p>Autodesk&rsquo;s CEO, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Bass">Carl Bass</a>, might just be the perfect guy to have at the helm for such a mission. He has an amazing workshop in West Berkeley and some interesting thoughts on the intersection of physical and digital creation:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Quotes on Journalism: One Old, One New]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/29/two-quotes-on-journalism/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T17:10:57-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/29/two-quotes-on-journalism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy <a href="http://www.usa.gov/Citizen/Topics/Voting.shtml">Election Day</a>. Below are two quotes on the subject of journalism, one from a great mind of the present, and one from a great mind of the past.</p>

<h4>From the present:</h4>

<blockquote><p>The post-fact literature is built in part on nostalgia for the world before people like Bigfoot showed up in the public sphere, for the days when Newsweek reflected moderately liberal consensus without also providing a platform for orthographically-challenged wingnuts to rant about the President. People who want those days back tell themselves (and anyone else who will listen) that they don’t want to impose their views on anybody. They just want agreement on the facts.
&hellip;
There’s no way to get Cronkite-like consensus without someone like Cronkite, and there’s no way to get someone like Cronkite in a world with an Internet; there will be no more men like him, because there will be no more jobs like his. To assume that this situation can be reversed, and everyone else will voluntarily sign on to the beliefs of some culturally dominant group, is a fantasy. To assume that they should, or at least that they should hold their tongue when they don’t, is Napoleonic in its self-regard. <strong>Yet this is what the people who long for the clarity of the old days are longing for.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p><strong>—Clay Shirky</strong>, Oct. 17th, 2012
from <em><a href="http://www.poynter.org/latest-news/everyday-ethics/191757/shirky-we-are-indeed-less-willing-to-agree-on-what-constitutes-truth/">‘We are indeed less willing to agree on what constitutes truth’</a></em></p>

<h4>From the past:</h4>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I can hardly regret having escaped the appalling waste of time and spirit which would have been involved in reading the war news or taking more than an artificial and formal part in conversations about the war. To read without military knowledge or good maps accounts of fighting which were distorted before they reached the Divisional general and further distorted before they left him and then &#8220;written up&rdquo; out of all recognition by jounralists, to strive to master what will be contradicted the next day, to fear and hope intensely on shaky evidence, is surely an ill use of the mind.</p></blockquote>

<p>Even in peacetime <strong>I think those are very wrong who say that schoolboys should be encouraged to read the newspapers. Nearly all that a boy reads there in his teens will be known before he is twenty to have been false in emphasis and interpretation, if not in fact as well, and most of it will have lost all importance. Most of what he remembers he will therefore have to unlearn; and he will probably have acquired a taste for vulgarity and sensationalism</strong> and the fatal habit of fluttering from paragraph to paragraph to learn how an heiress has been divorced in California, a train derailed in France, and quadruplets born in New Zealand.&#8221;</p>

<p><strong>—CS Lewis</strong>, 1966
from <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Surprised-Joy-Shape-Early-Life/dp/0156870118">Surprised by Joy</a></em></p>

<p>It seems that the clarity of the old days might not have been so clear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maine Sea]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/25/maine-sea-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-25T09:10:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/25/maine-sea-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The last stop on our Northeastern tour found us in <a href="http://www.nps.gov/acad/index.htm">Acadia National Park</a>. We stayed on both the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schoodic_Peninsula">Shoodic Peninsula</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Desert_Island">Mount Desert Island</a> sides of the park, and found the Schoodic area to be much quieter and less touristy.</p></blockquote>

<p>I <a href="http://ericdodds.com/maine-mountains-2012/">posted photos</a> of Acadia&rsquo;s mountains previously, but that was only half the story. Maritime heritage is the true treasure of Maine&rsquo;s coastline. I recommend steering clear of Bar Harbor and retreating to active fishing towns like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bass_Harbor,_Maine">Bass Harbor</a>, which we found to be quaint, full of history, and a great way to access offshore islands.</p>

<p>Fun fact: Bass Harbor was once <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bass_Harbor,_Maine">haphazardly named McKinley</a>, after President William McKinley. At the turn of the 20th century, federal officers asked what they should name the village&rsquo;s newly built post office. Someone in their company told them to &ldquo;name it after the president, for all we care.&rdquo; And they did. The town carried the same name until citizens petitioned to have it changed in 1961.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024897102/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8298/8024897102_bd064034a3_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-04 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 1 08" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024901061/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8175/8024901061_f6e0efdfdb_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-04 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 1 35" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024900065/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8304/8024900065_8b70e888c6_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-04 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 1 21" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024900337/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8182/8024900337_da4321ff30_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-04 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 1 23" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024899678/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8180/8024899678_b1473d2016_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-04 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 1 40" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024912138/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8312/8024912138_442203f8b3_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-05 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 2 48" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024950192/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8031/8024950192_eef11eb900_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-06 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 3 01" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024952225/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8455/8024952225_c4f2090d1c_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-06 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 3 05" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024951488/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8309/8024951488_bc04cd75f4_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-06 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 3 19" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024953359/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8035/8024953359_b161cb61f6_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-06 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 3 24" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024952106/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8453/8024952106_65f17a4204_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-06 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 3 35" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024952770/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8316/8024952770_6b4fdedf68_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-06 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 3 49" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025009620/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8181/8025009620_e6e88072cb_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 02" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025011499/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8041/8025011499_741b16c130_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 03" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025010290/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8034/8025010290_ea4b7425a9_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 05" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025010666/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8455/8025010666_f96608aa7b_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 10" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025012092/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8446/8025012092_86d7e3b9d4_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 28" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Follow Your Procrastination (Or, How I Changed Careers)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/14/follow-your-procrastination/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T11:21:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/14/follow-your-procrastination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago my friend posted a quote about procrastination:</p>

<blockquote><p>The work you do while you procrastinate is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life. <strong>–Jessica Hische</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>Upon first read the concept was interesting, but it&rsquo;s full weight didn&rsquo;t hit me until much later. I think the delayed reaction was due to my professional youth &ndash; at the time I was earning spurs on my first national brand and consuming knowledge from my veteran boss like a dry sponge. The specificity of the industry (marketing) was far less important to me than the unique opportunities I had to carry more responsibility than normal for my age.</p>

<p>After a good while, though, my rate of absorption began to slow. As a wise man <a href="http://gim.ie/5CIK">once said</a>, &ldquo;<em>in this department of life, as in every other, thrills come at the beginning and do not last.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>While I still thoroughly enjoyed my day-to-day responsibilities, a flattened learning curve afforded me more time to expand my reading and thinking about marketing, business, and more. Interestingly, my curiosity led me mostly towards the internet, technology, and entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>Hacker News and WIRED became regular reads, I began grabbing lunch with startup addicts like <a href="http://doddcaldwell.com">Dodd Caldwell</a>. I even started teaching myself basic HTML.</p>

<p>I also channeled my off-hours energy (and learning) into attempts to start a few companies. I began to scan my day-to-day experiences for annoyances or problems that I thought technology could iron out. At the time, I also happened to live with one of the most talented developers I&rsquo;ve ever met, and he was happy for a few new challenges to tackle.</p>

<p>In about a years&#8217; time, we both began and killed a rental payment web app and a wedding website service. (It was awesomely deflating to see Wordpress release a <a href="http://weddings.wordpress.com">phenomenal wedding product</a> not too long after we started writing code.)</p>

<p>Around that same time a friend told me that he heard about an extra volunteer spot at a sold-out conference called <a href="http://grok.cc">GROK</a>. I knew that some of the brightest minds in the country gather there to talk about technology, design, and the internet, so I was thrilled to take him up.</p>

<p>GROK did two very important things for me: First, it fully confirmed my passion for the industry, giving me clear direction for my next career move.</p>

<p>Second, it introduced me to a few gentleman named <a href="http://matthewsmith.cc">Matthew Smith</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/peterbarth">Peter Barth</a>, who would later provide the opportunity for that career move.</p>

<p>In different spheres, both had been forging a foundation of design and technology in the Upstate, Matthew through gathering some of the top talent in the nation and forming <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com">CoWork</a>, and Peter through a startup accelerator called The Next Big Thing.</p>

<p>When our paths crossed at GROK, it just so happens that they were talking about combining forces to form a single organization that shared resources, collaboration, and talent to better position our community as the place for all things tech in the Southeast.</p>

<p>It also just so happens that they needed another team member to manage both execution and promotion of their programs.</p>

<p>At that point, though, the merger was still an idea over lunch. But lunches turned into meetings, and meetings turned into branding work, and <a href="http://theironyard.com">The Iron Yard</a> was born, along with an offer for yours truly.</p>

<p>In November my procrastination will turn into my paycheck, and I couldn&rsquo;t be more excited.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Grown Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/all-grown-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-09T11:35:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/all-grown-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had an updated photo taken for my profile on the Brains on Fire website. My previous shot was over 4 years old, and I thought it would be fun to share both. Please note the electrical tape holding the saddle together in the hippie shot.</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/collage.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/collage.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>_Bonus: me riding a bike through the office at night. _</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/eric-new-night.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/eric-new-night.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maine Mountains]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/02/maine-mountains-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T12:24:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/02/maine-mountains-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The second stop on our Northeastern tour found us in <a href="http://www.nps.gov/acad/index.htm">Acadia National Park</a>. We stayed on both the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schoodic_Peninsula">Shoodic Peninsula</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Desert_Island">Mount Desert Island</a> sides of the park, and found the Schoodic area to be much quieter and less touristy.</p>

<p>Fun fact: The highest point in Acadia, Cadillac Mountain, is named for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antoine_Laumet_de_La_Mothe,_sieur_de_Cadillac">Antoine Laumet de La Mothe, sieur de Cadillac</a>, a French explorer. Along with leaving his namesake in Maine, he helped found the city of Detroit in the early 1700s. An automobile manufacturer honored the effort in 1902 by naming their firm &ldquo;Cadillac&rdquo; and using de La Mothe&rsquo;s coat of arms as their logo.</p>

<p>Here are a few photos from the hills.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025010417/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8171/8025010417_baffd42254_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 49" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024913511/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8173/8024913511_5316eb7e8b_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-05 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 2 28" /></a></p>

<p>The intersection of mountain and sea in Acadia is extraordinary.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024911090/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8316/8024911090_58ed7d3d08_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-05 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 2 02" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024912028/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8304/8024912028_cedf56b987_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-05 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 2 43" /></a></p>

<p>We missed the show, unfortunately.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025010639/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8450/8025010639_abf1803149_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 51" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025012754/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8031/8025012754_d0ab783dbf_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 41" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8025014825/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8452/8025014825_266ab4c850_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-07 Vacation - Maine:Acadia - Day 4 48" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Hampshire]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/09/26/new-hampshire-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T17:18:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/09/26/new-hampshire-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I recently went on an adventure in the Northeastern US. Our first stop was the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franconia_Ridge">Franconia Range</a> in New Hampshire&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_Mountains_(New_Hampshire">White Mountain National Forest</a>). The terrain was simultaneously some of the most challenging and beautiful I&rsquo;ve ever experienced. Fun fact: the highest surface wind speed observed by mankind (231mph) was <a href="http://www.mountwashington.org/about/visitor/recordwind.php">recorded in 1934</a> on Mount Washington, the highest peak in both the White Mountains and the Northeastern US.</p>

<p>Here are a few photos from our trip.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024790852/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8309/8024790852_311e88b8a7_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-01 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 1 - 08" /></a></p>

<p>Weather changes dangerously fast in these hills.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024793111/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8321/8024793111_8a1ed9d051_b.jpg" alt="2012-09-01 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 1 - 17" /></a></p>

<p>Steep and rocky.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024793301/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8170/8024793301_e02bd53144_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-01 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 1 - 29" /></a></p>

<p>Note the small hut just under the rock face in the center of the picture.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024793519/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8035/8024793519_62429cbd04_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-01 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 1 - 40" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024792636/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8179/8024792636_57ec704690_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-01 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 1 - 47" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024808108/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8174/8024808108_883198c817_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-02 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 2 - 01" /></a></p>

<p>The lakes of clouds were other-worldly.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024808922/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8178/8024808922_40b16b4d1b_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-02 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 2 - 07" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024811259/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8182/8024811259_884a1c3cbc_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-02 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 2 - 10" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024810186/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8174/8024810186_990e556d2d_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-02 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 2 - 20" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ericdodds/8024810536/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8319/8024810536_cabf7164dc_c.jpg" alt="2012-09-02 Vacation - New Hampshire Day 2 - 23" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["No Questions Asked" as a Clue to Your Standards]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/09/25/no-questions-asked-as-a-clue-to-your-standards/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T12:10:37-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/09/25/no-questions-asked-as-a-clue-to-your-standards</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week my wife and I joined my parents for dinner at a fairly new restaurant on the lake.</p>

<p>Aside from the privilege of enjoying a meal on the water, the experience was expected for a young establishment: decent service from a learning staff, and a well-prepared dish for a fair price.</p>

<p>When the manager came by to ask about our experience, he noticed that 5 people were waiting for a 6th person&rsquo;s meal to arrive before eating. Without any hesitation, he said: &ldquo;<em>Your meal is on us. I apologize.</em>&rdquo; Upon return, our waiter was fully aware of the comped dinner and offered an additional apology.</p>

<p>Several days later I received a call from SCBT, my bank. The conversation was short: &ldquo;<em>One of your checking accounts has been overdrawn. First, we wanted to know that you are a valued customer and this is abnormal, so we have waived the fee. We also want to let you know that you should transfer money into the account to avoid future fees.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>No inquiry about what happened, no discussion of the charge that overdrew the account, just a waived fee for a valued customer. No questions asked.</p>

<p>The areas in which you serve people without requiring explanation reveals your standards as a company or professional. (Or person, for that matter.)</p>

<p>There will always be people who take advantage of superior service. But companies who resolve to have the highest standard of treatment have <em>already</em> counted the cost of both their inevitable imperfection as well as the client&rsquo;s, and have built them into the business plan and employee culture.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fair Weather Doesn't Test the Sailor]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/09/20/fair-weather-doesnt-test-the-sailor/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T11:35:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/09/20/fair-weather-doesnt-test-the-sailor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My dad has a good friend who is a veterinarian. He once told a story about something his assistant said during a standard neutering operation:</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ve seen you perform that operation hundreds of times. I know it backwards and forwards. I&rsquo;m positive I could perform it by myself.</p></blockquote>

<p>The doctor understood that this was more a question than a statement, and responded accordingly:</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;m positive that you have the knowledge and skill to perform the operation as well. The difference between you and me, however, is that you don&rsquo;t know what to do if something goes wrong.</p></blockquote>

<p>GoDaddy&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.inc.com/jeremy-quittner/small-firms-shafted-in-godaddy-outage.html">recent server outage</a> was a great reminder that excellent work in good circumstances is no guarantee of satisfied customers. (Then again, neither are their products when things are normal, but I digress.) In short, how your company handles problems might be the best test of your team:</p>

<blockquote><p>Adversity cause some men to break; others to break records.
—William A Ward</p></blockquote>

<p>The good news is that if your walls are shored for good and bad weather, you can use storms as an opportunity to remind people that you have their best interest in mind.</p>

<p>And if you if you&rsquo;re really good, you show them with a dash of humor:</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/asana-server-fix.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/asana-server-fix.jpg" alt="" /></a>
<em>An error message clever (and simple) enough to make me smile. Great reaction from someone who needs your broken service.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morning Routine]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/31/morning-routine/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T12:00:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/31/morning-routine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A delightful morning ritual.</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Making-coffee-abstract-720px.png"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Making-coffee-abstract-720px.png" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pay Attention When the Peddler is Hungry]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/29/pay-attention-when-the-peddler-is-hungry/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-29T10:26:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/29/pay-attention-when-the-peddler-is-hungry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago I had the chance to talk with a subsidiary of the company <a href="http://usa.autodesk.com">Autodesk</a>. A representative contacted me about co-promotion, and even though my gut told me our budget restraints would end the conversation quickly, I humored the opportunity.</p>

<p>The offer was surprising: promote our project to their gigantic audience for free.</p>

<p>Having entertained similar opportunities in the past, the one-sidedness of the deal seemed odd. Nonetheless, the potential benefit was attractive. So our team discussed, developed a low-impact test, and took a hopeful step forward. Throughout the process, my anecdotal research on Autodesk kept the peculiarity of the offer in the back of my mind &ndash; what would their seemingly successful business want with our relatively new (and small) project?</p>

<p>In the end, the trial showed that our audiences didn&rsquo;t align well. Despite more conversation, we stopped pursuing the relationship.</p>

<p>Then, the other morning, I read that Autodesk <a href="http://www.wired.com/design/2012/08/autodesk-layoffs/">is laying off a sizable number of employees</a>. Of course, the company&rsquo;s restructuring, forecasting, and falling stock issues may have nothing at all to with the odd opportunity we had. Even the if the potential of the relationship was realized it wouldn&rsquo;t have blipped on the radar screens of top brass.</p>

<p>Either way, the coincidence was a great reminder: pay attention when opportunity paints the peddler hungry.</p>

<hr />

<p>_Speaking of paying attention to hunger, I would be remiss not to mention <a href="http://ricebowls.org">Rice Bowls</a>. They provide food to orphaned children, and I&rsquo;m a proud supporter of their effort. _</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Like Working Out, But it Makes Me Better at My Job]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/i-dont-like-working-out-but-it-makes-me-better-at-my-job/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T07:41:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/i-dont-like-working-out-but-it-makes-me-better-at-my-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s get one thing straight: I&rsquo;m a scrawny human being. Weights have never looked favorably on my lanky appendages, and even if they did I&rsquo;d look like a freak with cantaloupe biceps. Despite the physiological cards I&rsquo;ve been dealt, though, I still do strength training three times a week.</p>

<p>Recently my wife pointed out something she (and I) found interesting (we&rsquo;ve been married 5 months so new discoveries abound): I don&rsquo;t have any specific goals for strength training. I&rsquo;m not a fitness junkie, I don&rsquo;t have a need or desire to get super strong, I don&rsquo;t need to lose weight or change the way I look, and the health benefit isn&rsquo;t imperative &ndash; our lifestyle is filled with other aerobic activity several times a week (running, biking, hiking, etc.). So, understandably, she asked why I still train so consistently. Or, more bluntly, why would I put myself through pain when I didn&rsquo;t really need to?</p>

<p>Up until then, my thoughts on the subject hadn&rsquo;t traveled outside my own head, so synthesizing them and communicating them was an interesting exercise. My response went something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>I think I work out because choosing to do something I really don&rsquo;t want to do, something that is consistently difficult and painful to overcome, makes the other battles in work and life easier to face and overcome.</p></blockquote>

<p>In short, the battle of working out develops a fitness in difficulty that pays dividends when other battles happen at work and home.</p>

<p>Sure, I feel good after a workout, but I don&rsquo;t love heaving out pull ups or wincing through lunges. I do think, though, that the discipline of mind in hardship makes me a better employee, boss, and husband.</p>

<p><em>(Well, that and the fact that I can still beat both of my brothers arm wrestling. I&rsquo;ve never beat my dad, but time and age virtually guarantee a win at some point. Yes, that anticipation is clearly horrible and unfair, but family rivalries are family rivalries.)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewind: The Most Valuable Gift You Can Give Your Employees - Commentary]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/15/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees-commentary/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T14:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/15/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees-commentary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I re-posted the very first article I wrote as a young and overly optimistic youth, freshly released into the bitter reality of life in a marketing agency. (Go back and <a href="http://ericdodds.com/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees/">have a read</a> if you like.)</p>

<p>Today I said that I would share what I hope is mature, growth-inspired commentary. Again, no promises.</p>

<hr />

<p>Well, 22-year-old Eric, article really isn&rsquo;t too shabby. You&rsquo;d be glad to know that I still wholeheartedly believe that freedom to fail is an incredible asset to employees.</p>

<p>Both supervisors I&rsquo;ve had at Brains on Fire have, I believe, helped me learn more quickly than I would have at other places by letting me try to climb hills too big for my age and title when I asked.</p>

<p><em>A few thoughts:</em></p>

<p>First of all, I now have a direct report. I actually hired this person because they cold-called me, but that&rsquo;s another story for another time.</p>

<p>Not being responsible for myself and my work only has helped me see that the real utility in offering someone the chance to fail is in the learning. I do think the opportunity produces better work in the long run, but lessons learned in the process are as valuable, if not more, than the final product. Being a nice boss isn&rsquo;t that hard. Helping your team grow is tough, and doing the extra work of wading through the process of &lsquo;failure&rsquo; can be extremely demanding. It&rsquo;s also hard to ensure that individual failure doesn&rsquo;t compromise the quality (or timing) of what is delivered to the client or customer. In my experience, these challenges are worth the expense.</p>

<p>Another thing I&rsquo;ve learned since writing the article is that implementing this concept company-wide is extremely difficult. Not many businesses have successfully scaled a culture that allows their employees &ndash; especially those on the front line &ndash; to take risks. And really, that is a question of scaling leadership. For most people at most work places, the best chance at offering people opportunity exists on their own teams. My good friend Jamie Plesser (who works at a giant corporation) <a href="http://kcslim.posterous.com/94532739">says it well</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Now by doing this am I going to affect a sea change in the organization?  Likely not.  But I can make a difference for my team.  I can encourage them to take charge and own their own time.  Plus I can push others in the company to reevaluate [long-standing inefficient processes].</p></blockquote>

<p>Interestingly, many in leadership positions seem to view this process (and work) of employee growth as additional to the work &lsquo;they already have to do.&rsquo; Hogwash. I believe that if you are in a position of leadership, the growth and development of the people you lead is one of your foremost responsibilities, and, really, privileges. If not, you&rsquo;re simply a manager.</p>

<hr />

<p><em>That was a fun look back, and it almost seems like there&rsquo;s some learning in all of that pontification. I just might find another old article to post here soon. </em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewind: The Most Valuable Gift You Can Give Your Employees]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-14T00:28:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I launched the new site and told people that I&rsquo;d actually write things,  I&rsquo;ve spent time reviewing older articles I&rsquo;ve written for <a href="http://ericdodds.com/projects/brains-on-fire-internal/">Brains on Fire</a>. I thought it might be an entertaining (and maybe even educational) exercise to re-post some of my younger ramblings now that I&rsquo;ve convinced at least a few people that I&rsquo;ve matured.</p>

<p>So, on that note, below is the first article I wrote as a professional in the real world. (I&rsquo;ve edited out some of the superfluous fluff.)</p>

<p><del>Tomorrow I&rsquo;ll post</del> (you can see my attempt <a href="http://ericdodds.com/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees-commentary/">here</a>) what I hope will be mature, growth-inspired commentary. No promises.</p>

<blockquote><p>“<em>The most valuable gift you can give your employees is permission to fail.</em>”</p></blockquote>

<p>When my friend <a href="http://joshuablankenship.com/blog/">Joshua Blankenship</a> said that to me during my last term at university I didn’t fully understand what he meant, and to be honest, it didn’t settle well in my brain at first hearing.</p>

<p>I think part of my problem was that our society views failure primarily as a negative concept. Think about it – if you reflect on your education from kindergarten to university, most students have been taught through experience that the worst thing you could do as a student is fail. The famous red “F” with a circle around it at the top of your paper. I don’t think anyone is denying that earning high marks is generally a good thing and poor performance bears negative consequences, but what if our society’s view of failure is wrong? What if the red “F” is actually a healthy thing sometimes?</p>

<p>I was recently hired as part of the insight and research team here at Brains on Fire. Within the first few weeks on the job my boss, <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/54084/fast-talk-voices-creative-front-lines">Dr. Justine Foo</a>, asked me to perform research and write a report for a national client. Though capable, I was green (still am), and in the fear of failure I learned so well through education, I began to ask her questions every 10 minutes about the project and what I should do (remember that Justine?).</p>

<p>After a few interruptions, she sat me down and gave me some of the best advice I have ever received: “<em>Eric, we didn’t hire you so that you would ask me a thousand questions and be unsure about what you are doing. We hired you to produce amazing work. And you are fully capable of doing that. So, if you have a legitimate question, ask me. If not, just produce amazing work. And if you get it wrong, I’ll show you where, why and how to fix it, and you’ll grow.</em>”</p>

<p>Freedom.</p>

<p>The freedom to create my best work was born out of granted freedom to fail in my attempt.</p>

<p>Not cavalier freedom to do whatever I want, but freedom to give our clients the best (and most effective) work they have ever seen.</p>

<p>I have found that my greatest achievements are possible because my greatest failures are possible. So, you were right Joshua. I understand what you meant a lot better now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
