<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Work | Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-19T13:53:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailbox App and the Illusion of Moving Information]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/mailbox-app-and-the-illusion-of-moving-information/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T14:50:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/mailbox-app-and-the-illusion-of-moving-information</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently downloaded the much anticipated Mailbox app. It&rsquo;s a fine tool, designed well, with a pretty slick interface. Arguably, the most exciting feature of the product is it&rsquo;s ability to &lsquo;snooze&rsquo; messages and bring them back at various intervals. Selling the idea of an easily attainable inbox zero made a lot of people salivate.</p>

<p><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_0870-e1362685058726.jpg" alt="IMG_0870" /></p>

<p>Hopefully the app helps people, but I don&rsquo;t think it will solve one of the real problems (especially for teams) that we have with email, which is the tendency to use it as a to-do list &ndash; the <a href="http://mailboxapp.com/story">primary reason creators gave</a> for building the app.</p>

<p>People are hungry for help because of the volume of email they receive. The medium has grown from an efficient person-to-person communication tool to a firehose of unrelated information from any and every possible source (including physical devices). Lots of that information needs to be acted on, not just consumed. Figuring out how to deal with the constant stream can be a tall task.</p>

<p>Dealing with information and moving it around are two different things, though. Snoozing an email for a week is great, until you&rsquo;ve snoozed it every week for a month straight. At that point you&rsquo;ve given yourself a pat on the back for cleaning your inbox, when all you&rsquo;ve done is temporarily hidden something you need to do.</p>

<p>Feeling good about hiding an email you need to act on is the same as feeling good about neatly labeling and filing past-due bills you need to pay.</p>

<p>Tools like Mailbox do a great job of helping you move things around in a logical, efficient way. That&rsquo;s great for individuals who use email mostly on their mobile devices, but it&rsquo;s a far cry from <a href="http://visualidiot.com/articles/mailappapp">revolutionizing the tool itself</a>, especially for teams working on complex projects.</p>

<p><del>The opportunity is so much larger than improving the moving process. We need tools that remove the manual labor associated with translating that information into the actions that move strategies forward and produce products and services. Right now that process is clunky, and the pain is magnified on mobile devices.</del></p>

<p><del>Apps that allow creation of to-do&rsquo;s via email are a step in the right direction, but still require some manual labor and processing. <a href="http://www.taskforceapp.com/">Taskforce</a> is an interesting solution, but keeps email in the browser, and seems much less robust than Asana or Trello. (I&rsquo;d love to hear about other solutions I haven&rsquo;t come across.)</del></p>

<p>UPDATE:</p>

<p>Of course, this is the internet, and everything exists. Both <a href="http://do.com">do.com</a> and <a href="http://www.producteev.com/">Producteev</a> provide pretty slick Gmail gadgets that allow you to turn emails into tasks.</p>

<p>The more I&rsquo;ve heard people talk about the Mailbox app, the more I&rsquo;ve noticed complaints that &ldquo;it screwed up Gmail on my computer.&rdquo; The aggravated users are referring to labels, and the specific way in which Mailbox uses them to categorize messages. Even though there was an explanation in the onboarding process, I&rsquo;ve run across a surprising number of people who deleted the app because the user flow didn&rsquo;t translate well between mobile and desktop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Differences in Distance at My New Work Space]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/01/04/three-differences-in-distance-at-my-new-work-space/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T12:59:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/01/04/three-differences-in-distance-at-my-new-work-space</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>1) Distance from home</h4>

<p>My old job was about .6 miles from my house. I biked to work most days, and often told my wife that I was trying to enjoy a rare proximity to the office that I might not experience again. And then I went to work at The Iron Yard, and my <em>commute became even shorter</em>.</p>

<p>To get from my front door to my desk takes approximately 5 and a half minutes on foot, or 755 steps, at a leisurely pace. It&rsquo;s so great that I almost feel bad telling you about it. Almost.</p>

<h4>2) Distance to the water closet</h4>

<p>This is petty, but the bathroom is a lot closer than it used to be. It&rsquo;s convenient. I drink a lot of water. Sue me.</p>

<h4>3) Distance to coffee</h4>

<p>Some people might argue that being close to coffee in the morning is a basic human right, but those people probably aren&rsquo;t human until they&rsquo;ve had their coffee, so it doesn&rsquo;t matter. I really like coffee, and I have to walk almost 3 times further to get to it in the new office. That means I drink less of it, which means my teeth won&rsquo;t brown as quickly as I age. Inconvenient, but a win.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I've Been Up To at the New Gig]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/what-ive-been-up-to-at-the-new-gig/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T16:47:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/what-ive-been-up-to-at-the-new-gig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last month has been a bit wild, what with <a href="http://ericdodds.com/follow-your-procrastination/">diving into a new industry</a> and all. Here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve been up to:</p>

<p>—Building a workflow and project management system that works for our team.
<em>We&rsquo;ve tried app after app, but the current system of <a href="https://trello.com">Trello</a> + <a href="https://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> + <a href="%22https://dispatch.io">Dispatch</a> + <a href="%22http://voxer.com">Voxer</a> seems to get the job done. Coming from a place where process was inflexible, working with a small team who&rsquo;s willing to change has been delightful.</em></p>

<p>—Organizing <em>everything</em>
<em>File here, file there, file, file everywhere! Grunt work, but important grunt work. I&rsquo;m almost obsessive-compulsive about file structure and organization, and being able to build a clean and flexible structure from the beginning makes life oh-so-much easier.</em></p>

<p>—Setting up bank accounts, payroll, and health benefits</p>

<p>—Planning up-fit for two separate office locations, including layout and broad design
<em>Including designing a very cost-effective desk design using black pipe and fittings (like <a href="http://theironyard.com/2012/11/its-time-to-take-a-stand-cowork-standing-desks/">this</a>, but cheaper)</em></p>

<p>—Researching investors and startups in the Southeast</p>

<p>—Attending the <a href="http://theironyard.com/2012/11/what-the-iron-yard-learned-at-the-gan-founders-conference/">GAN Founders Conference</a> in Boston (and eating some really good food while I was there)</p>

<p>—Writing (for <a href="http://www.gsabusiness.com">GSA Business</a> and <a href="http://theironyard.com/blog/">The Iron Yard</a>)</p>

<p>—Dreaming with the <a href="http://coderdojogreenville.com">CoderDojo crew</a> about teaching people more people to code</p>

<p>—Laying the groundwork for <a href="http://grok.cc">Grok 2013</a></p>

<p>—Re-branding The Iron Yard (coming soon to an internet near you)
<em>I had the chance to work with <a href="http://twitter.com/whale">Matthew Smith</a> and <a href="http://dribbble.com/justinhall">Justin Hall</a> to on the logo and visual elements (more on that soon), and I worked with Peter Barth to craft our positioning (more on that soon, too).</em></p>

<p>—Building a content strategy, marketing, and PR plan for The Iron Yard</p>

<p>—Reading a good amount of tech news</p>

<p>—Brainstorming with the <a href="http://ridepost.com">RidePost</a> crew about copy and user experience for a new feature</p>

<p>—Talking and writing with <a href="http://danwaldschmidt.com">Dan Waldschmidt</a> on his new project</p>

<p>—<a href="http://daytum.com/displays/274600">Walking a lot</a>.</p>

<p>I work harder and come home happier than I ever have before.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Follow Your Procrastination (Or, How I Changed Careers)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/14/follow-your-procrastination/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T11:21:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/14/follow-your-procrastination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago my friend posted a quote about procrastination:</p>

<blockquote><p>The work you do while you procrastinate is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life. <strong>–Jessica Hische</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>Upon first read the concept was interesting, but it&rsquo;s full weight didn&rsquo;t hit me until much later. I think the delayed reaction was due to my professional youth &ndash; at the time I was earning spurs on my first national brand and consuming knowledge from my veteran boss like a dry sponge. The specificity of the industry (marketing) was far less important to me than the unique opportunities I had to carry more responsibility than normal for my age.</p>

<p>After a good while, though, my rate of absorption began to slow. As a wise man <a href="http://gim.ie/5CIK">once said</a>, &ldquo;<em>in this department of life, as in every other, thrills come at the beginning and do not last.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>While I still thoroughly enjoyed my day-to-day responsibilities, a flattened learning curve afforded me more time to expand my reading and thinking about marketing, business, and more. Interestingly, my curiosity led me mostly towards the internet, technology, and entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>Hacker News and WIRED became regular reads, I began grabbing lunch with startup addicts like <a href="http://doddcaldwell.com">Dodd Caldwell</a>. I even started teaching myself basic HTML.</p>

<p>I also channeled my off-hours energy (and learning) into attempts to start a few companies. I began to scan my day-to-day experiences for annoyances or problems that I thought technology could iron out. At the time, I also happened to live with one of the most talented developers I&rsquo;ve ever met, and he was happy for a few new challenges to tackle.</p>

<p>In about a years' time, we both began and killed a rental payment web app and a wedding website service. (It was awesomely deflating to see Wordpress release a <a href="http://weddings.wordpress.com">phenomenal wedding product</a> not too long after we started writing code.)</p>

<p>Around that same time a friend told me that he heard about an extra volunteer spot at a sold-out conference called <a href="http://grok.cc">GROK</a>. I knew that some of the brightest minds in the country gather there to talk about technology, design, and the internet, so I was thrilled to take him up.</p>

<p>GROK did two very important things for me: First, it fully confirmed my passion for the industry, giving me clear direction for my next career move.</p>

<p>Second, it introduced me to a few gentleman named <a href="http://matthewsmith.cc">Matthew Smith</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/peterbarth">Peter Barth</a>, who would later provide the opportunity for that career move.</p>

<p>In different spheres, both had been forging a foundation of design and technology in the Upstate, Matthew through gathering some of the top talent in the nation and forming <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com">CoWork</a>, and Peter through a startup accelerator called The Next Big Thing.</p>

<p>When our paths crossed at GROK, it just so happens that they were talking about combining forces to form a single organization that shared resources, collaboration, and talent to better position our community as the place for all things tech in the Southeast.</p>

<p>It also just so happens that they needed another team member to manage both execution and promotion of their programs.</p>

<p>At that point, though, the merger was still an idea over lunch. But lunches turned into meetings, and meetings turned into branding work, and <a href="http://theironyard.com">The Iron Yard</a> was born, along with an offer for yours truly.</p>

<p>In November my procrastination will turn into my paycheck, and I couldn&rsquo;t be more excited.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pay Attention When the Peddler is Hungry]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/29/pay-attention-when-the-peddler-is-hungry/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-29T10:26:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/29/pay-attention-when-the-peddler-is-hungry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago I had the chance to talk with a subsidiary of the company <a href="http://usa.autodesk.com">Autodesk</a>. A representative contacted me about co-promotion, and even though my gut told me our budget restraints would end the conversation quickly, I humored the opportunity.</p>

<p>The offer was surprising: promote our project to their gigantic audience for free.</p>

<p>Having entertained similar opportunities in the past, the one-sidedness of the deal seemed odd. Nonetheless, the potential benefit was attractive. So our team discussed, developed a low-impact test, and took a hopeful step forward. Throughout the process, my anecdotal research on Autodesk kept the peculiarity of the offer in the back of my mind &ndash; what would their seemingly successful business want with our relatively new (and small) project?</p>

<p>In the end, the trial showed that our audiences didn&rsquo;t align well. Despite more conversation, we stopped pursuing the relationship.</p>

<p>Then, the other morning, I read that Autodesk <a href="http://www.wired.com/design/2012/08/autodesk-layoffs/">is laying off a sizable number of employees</a>. Of course, the company&rsquo;s restructuring, forecasting, and falling stock issues may have nothing at all to with the odd opportunity we had. Even the if the potential of the relationship was realized it wouldn&rsquo;t have blipped on the radar screens of top brass.</p>

<p>Either way, the coincidence was a great reminder: pay attention when opportunity paints the peddler hungry.</p>

<hr />

<p>_Speaking of paying attention to hunger, I would be remiss not to mention <a href="http://ricebowls.org">Rice Bowls</a>. They provide food to orphaned children, and I&rsquo;m a proud supporter of their effort. _</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
