<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Rewind | Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/categories/rewind/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-19T13:53:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Grown Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/all-grown-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-09T11:35:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/all-grown-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had an updated photo taken for my profile on the Brains on Fire website. My previous shot was over 4 years old, and I thought it would be fun to share both. Please note the electrical tape holding the saddle together in the hippie shot.</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/collage.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/collage.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>_Bonus: me riding a bike through the office at night. _</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/eric-new-night.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/eric-new-night.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewind: The Most Valuable Gift You Can Give Your Employees - Commentary]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/15/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees-commentary/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T14:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/15/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees-commentary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I re-posted the very first article I wrote as a young and overly optimistic youth, freshly released into the bitter reality of life in a marketing agency. (Go back and <a href="http://ericdodds.com/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees/">have a read</a> if you like.)</p>

<p>Today I said that I would share what I hope is mature, growth-inspired commentary. Again, no promises.</p>

<hr />

<p>Well, 22-year-old Eric, article really isn&rsquo;t too shabby. You&rsquo;d be glad to know that I still wholeheartedly believe that freedom to fail is an incredible asset to employees.</p>

<p>Both supervisors I&rsquo;ve had at Brains on Fire have, I believe, helped me learn more quickly than I would have at other places by letting me try to climb hills too big for my age and title when I asked.</p>

<p><em>A few thoughts:</em></p>

<p>First of all, I now have a direct report. I actually hired this person because they cold-called me, but that&rsquo;s another story for another time.</p>

<p>Not being responsible for myself and my work only has helped me see that the real utility in offering someone the chance to fail is in the learning. I do think the opportunity produces better work in the long run, but lessons learned in the process are as valuable, if not more, than the final product. Being a nice boss isn&rsquo;t that hard. Helping your team grow is tough, and doing the extra work of wading through the process of &lsquo;failure&rsquo; can be extremely demanding. It&rsquo;s also hard to ensure that individual failure doesn&rsquo;t compromise the quality (or timing) of what is delivered to the client or customer. In my experience, these challenges are worth the expense.</p>

<p>Another thing I&rsquo;ve learned since writing the article is that implementing this concept company-wide is extremely difficult. Not many businesses have successfully scaled a culture that allows their employees &ndash; especially those on the front line &ndash; to take risks. And really, that is a question of scaling leadership. For most people at most work places, the best chance at offering people opportunity exists on their own teams. My good friend Jamie Plesser (who works at a giant corporation) <a href="http://kcslim.posterous.com/94532739">says it well</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Now by doing this am I going to affect a sea change in the organization?  Likely not.  But I can make a difference for my team.  I can encourage them to take charge and own their own time.  Plus I can push others in the company to reevaluate [long-standing inefficient processes].</p></blockquote>

<p>Interestingly, many in leadership positions seem to view this process (and work) of employee growth as additional to the work &lsquo;they already have to do.&rsquo; Hogwash. I believe that if you are in a position of leadership, the growth and development of the people you lead is one of your foremost responsibilities, and, really, privileges. If not, you&rsquo;re simply a manager.</p>

<hr />

<p><em>That was a fun look back, and it almost seems like there&rsquo;s some learning in all of that pontification. I just might find another old article to post here soon. </em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewind: The Most Valuable Gift You Can Give Your Employees]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-14T00:28:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I launched the new site and told people that I&rsquo;d actually write things,  I&rsquo;ve spent time reviewing older articles I&rsquo;ve written for <a href="http://ericdodds.com/projects/brains-on-fire-internal/">Brains on Fire</a>. I thought it might be an entertaining (and maybe even educational) exercise to re-post some of my younger ramblings now that I&rsquo;ve convinced at least a few people that I&rsquo;ve matured.</p>

<p>So, on that note, below is the first article I wrote as a professional in the real world. (I&rsquo;ve edited out some of the superfluous fluff.)</p>

<p><del>Tomorrow I&rsquo;ll post</del> (you can see my attempt <a href="http://ericdodds.com/rewind-the-most-valuable-gift-you-can-give-your-employees-commentary/">here</a>) what I hope will be mature, growth-inspired commentary. No promises.</p>

<blockquote><p>“<em>The most valuable gift you can give your employees is permission to fail.</em>”</p></blockquote>

<p>When my friend <a href="http://joshuablankenship.com/blog/">Joshua Blankenship</a> said that to me during my last term at university I didn’t fully understand what he meant, and to be honest, it didn’t settle well in my brain at first hearing.</p>

<p>I think part of my problem was that our society views failure primarily as a negative concept. Think about it – if you reflect on your education from kindergarten to university, most students have been taught through experience that the worst thing you could do as a student is fail. The famous red “F” with a circle around it at the top of your paper. I don’t think anyone is denying that earning high marks is generally a good thing and poor performance bears negative consequences, but what if our society’s view of failure is wrong? What if the red “F” is actually a healthy thing sometimes?</p>

<p>I was recently hired as part of the insight and research team here at Brains on Fire. Within the first few weeks on the job my boss, <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/54084/fast-talk-voices-creative-front-lines">Dr. Justine Foo</a>, asked me to perform research and write a report for a national client. Though capable, I was green (still am), and in the fear of failure I learned so well through education, I began to ask her questions every 10 minutes about the project and what I should do (remember that Justine?).</p>

<p>After a few interruptions, she sat me down and gave me some of the best advice I have ever received: “<em>Eric, we didn’t hire you so that you would ask me a thousand questions and be unsure about what you are doing. We hired you to produce amazing work. And you are fully capable of doing that. So, if you have a legitimate question, ask me. If not, just produce amazing work. And if you get it wrong, I’ll show you where, why and how to fix it, and you’ll grow.</em>”</p>

<p>Freedom.</p>

<p>The freedom to create my best work was born out of granted freedom to fail in my attempt.</p>

<p>Not cavalier freedom to do whatever I want, but freedom to give our clients the best (and most effective) work they have ever seen.</p>

<p>I have found that my greatest achievements are possible because my greatest failures are possible. So, you were right Joshua. I understand what you meant a lot better now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
