<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Journal | Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/categories/journal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-19T13:53:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailbox App and the Illusion of Moving Information]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/mailbox-app-and-the-illusion-of-moving-information/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T14:50:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/mailbox-app-and-the-illusion-of-moving-information</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently downloaded the much anticipated Mailbox app. It&rsquo;s a fine tool, designed well, with a pretty slick interface. Arguably, the most exciting feature of the product is it&rsquo;s ability to &lsquo;snooze&rsquo; messages and bring them back at various intervals. Selling the idea of an easily attainable inbox zero made a lot of people salivate.</p>

<p><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_0870-e1362685058726.jpg" alt="IMG_0870" /></p>

<p>Hopefully the app helps people, but I don&rsquo;t think it will solve one of the real problems (especially for teams) that we have with email, which is the tendency to use it as a to-do list &ndash; the <a href="http://mailboxapp.com/story">primary reason creators gave</a> for building the app.</p>

<p>People are hungry for help because of the volume of email they receive. The medium has grown from an efficient person-to-person communication tool to a firehose of unrelated information from any and every possible source (including physical devices). Lots of that information needs to be acted on, not just consumed. Figuring out how to deal with the constant stream can be a tall task.</p>

<p>Dealing with information and moving it around are two different things, though. Snoozing an email for a week is great, until you&rsquo;ve snoozed it every week for a month straight. At that point you&rsquo;ve given yourself a pat on the back for cleaning your inbox, when all you&rsquo;ve done is temporarily hidden something you need to do.</p>

<p>Feeling good about hiding an email you need to act on is the same as feeling good about neatly labeling and filing past-due bills you need to pay.</p>

<p>Tools like Mailbox do a great job of helping you move things around in a logical, efficient way. That&rsquo;s great for individuals who use email mostly on their mobile devices, but it&rsquo;s a far cry from <a href="http://visualidiot.com/articles/mailappapp">revolutionizing the tool itself</a>, especially for teams working on complex projects.</p>

<p><del>The opportunity is so much larger than improving the moving process. We need tools that remove the manual labor associated with translating that information into the actions that move strategies forward and produce products and services. Right now that process is clunky, and the pain is magnified on mobile devices.</del></p>

<p><del>Apps that allow creation of to-do&rsquo;s via email are a step in the right direction, but still require some manual labor and processing. <a href="http://www.taskforceapp.com/">Taskforce</a> is an interesting solution, but keeps email in the browser, and seems much less robust than Asana or Trello. (I&rsquo;d love to hear about other solutions I haven&rsquo;t come across.)</del></p>

<p>UPDATE:</p>

<p>Of course, this is the internet, and everything exists. Both <a href="http://do.com">do.com</a> and <a href="http://www.producteev.com/">Producteev</a> provide pretty slick Gmail gadgets that allow you to turn emails into tasks.</p>

<p>The more I&rsquo;ve heard people talk about the Mailbox app, the more I&rsquo;ve noticed complaints that &ldquo;it screwed up Gmail on my computer.&rdquo; The aggravated users are referring to labels, and the specific way in which Mailbox uses them to categorize messages. Even though there was an explanation in the onboarding process, I&rsquo;ve run across a surprising number of people who deleted the app because the user flow didn&rsquo;t translate well between mobile and desktop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Love is in the...Chinese Tech Company Culture? ]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/14/love-is-in-the-chinese-tech-company-culture/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T13:27:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/14/love-is-in-the-chinese-tech-company-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Company culture is incredibly important, and leaders have been known to allow very non-traditional activity to foster it. In China, one of those activities is encouraging love – the romantic kind – between their <em>employees</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Fast Company reports</strong> on Alibaba&rsquo;s annual mass weddings performed by their CEO:</p>

<blockquote><p>But Song was not the only woman wearing white at her wedding. In fact, she wasn&rsquo;t even the only bride. There were 324 others, all participating in a marriage ceremony led by Alibaba CEO Jack Ma, who performs a mass wedding for his employees every May. Song particularly remembers one thing Ma told the brides and grooms: &ldquo;Love is not something you say. It&rsquo;s something you do&mdash;starting tonight!&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><em><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1802729/leaders-alibaba-youku-and-baidu-are-slowly-shaking-chinas-corporate-culture">Read the full article here.</a></em></p>

<p><strong>A cloud computing company in Chengdu, China</strong> awards &ldquo;Love Bonuses&rdquo; to workers who fall in love:</p>

<blockquote><p>In China’s own Silicon Valley in Sichuan Province, the Chengdu cloud computing company has decided to reward its employees for falling in love, reports the People’s Daily.</p></blockquote>

<p>Chengdu executives told the People’s Daily, that they came up with the idea after seeing the emotional turmoil of his young workers, awarding a financial bonus for workers willing to tuoguang – “strip” – slang for saying goodbye to the single life. The company hopes that if their employees fall in love with their colleagues, they will “have an even more harmonious team”&hellip;</p>

<p><em><a href="http://worldcrunch.com/culture-society/chinese-tech-firm-gives-employees-quot-love-bonus-quot-to-hook-up/china-chengdu-it-workers-love-single/c3s10178/#.UKubo6WmC-L">Read the full article here.</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I've Been Up To at the New Gig]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/what-ive-been-up-to-at-the-new-gig/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T16:47:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/what-ive-been-up-to-at-the-new-gig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last month has been a bit wild, what with <a href="http://ericdodds.com/follow-your-procrastination/">diving into a new industry</a> and all. Here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve been up to:</p>

<p>—Building a workflow and project management system that works for our team.
<em>We&rsquo;ve tried app after app, but the current system of <a href="https://trello.com">Trello</a> + <a href="https://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> + <a href="%22https://dispatch.io">Dispatch</a> + <a href="%22http://voxer.com">Voxer</a> seems to get the job done. Coming from a place where process was inflexible, working with a small team who&rsquo;s willing to change has been delightful.</em></p>

<p>—Organizing <em>everything</em>
<em>File here, file there, file, file everywhere! Grunt work, but important grunt work. I&rsquo;m almost obsessive-compulsive about file structure and organization, and being able to build a clean and flexible structure from the beginning makes life oh-so-much easier.</em></p>

<p>—Setting up bank accounts, payroll, and health benefits</p>

<p>—Planning up-fit for two separate office locations, including layout and broad design
<em>Including designing a very cost-effective desk design using black pipe and fittings (like <a href="http://theironyard.com/2012/11/its-time-to-take-a-stand-cowork-standing-desks/">this</a>, but cheaper)</em></p>

<p>—Researching investors and startups in the Southeast</p>

<p>—Attending the <a href="http://theironyard.com/2012/11/what-the-iron-yard-learned-at-the-gan-founders-conference/">GAN Founders Conference</a> in Boston (and eating some really good food while I was there)</p>

<p>—Writing (for <a href="http://www.gsabusiness.com">GSA Business</a> and <a href="http://theironyard.com/blog/">The Iron Yard</a>)</p>

<p>—Dreaming with the <a href="http://coderdojogreenville.com">CoderDojo crew</a> about teaching people more people to code</p>

<p>—Laying the groundwork for <a href="http://grok.cc">Grok 2013</a></p>

<p>—Re-branding The Iron Yard (coming soon to an internet near you)
<em>I had the chance to work with <a href="http://twitter.com/whale">Matthew Smith</a> and <a href="http://dribbble.com/justinhall">Justin Hall</a> to on the logo and visual elements (more on that soon), and I worked with Peter Barth to craft our positioning (more on that soon, too).</em></p>

<p>—Building a content strategy, marketing, and PR plan for The Iron Yard</p>

<p>—Reading a good amount of tech news</p>

<p>—Brainstorming with the <a href="http://ridepost.com">RidePost</a> crew about copy and user experience for a new feature</p>

<p>—Talking and writing with <a href="http://danwaldschmidt.com">Dan Waldschmidt</a> on his new project</p>

<p>—<a href="http://daytum.com/displays/274600">Walking a lot</a>.</p>

<p>I work harder and come home happier than I ever have before.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Update on the Hungry Peddler]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/11/19/an-update-on-the-hungry-peddler/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T10:50:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/11/19/an-update-on-the-hungry-peddler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several months ago I <a href="http://ericdodds.com/pay-attention-when-the-peddler-is-hungry/">wrote about</a> Autodesk laying off 500 employees. An experience I had with one of their subsidiaries prior to the downsizing made wonder if I should&rsquo;ve sensed trouble, but it turns out my (admittedly) uninformed speculation was off base. From a <a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2012/09/ff-autodesk-and-the-big-make/">recent Wired feature</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>On paper, no firm is better positioned to take advantage of a maker-led future than Autodesk, whose 30 years of experience in <a href="http://usa.autodesk.com/adsk/servlet/item?siteID=123112&amp;id=17690382">computer-aided design</a> give it unparalleled intelligence about the capabilities that designers want and need in their software. Despite some recent financial travails (in August, <a href="http://investors.autodesk.com/phoenix.zhtml?c=117861&amp;p=irol-irhome">lower-than-expected earnings</a> forced the layoff of some 500 employees), Autodesk’s core professional business affords it enviable leeway to pursue the consumer market without jeopardizing its solvency.</p></blockquote>

<p>Autodesk&rsquo;s CEO, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Bass">Carl Bass</a>, might just be the perfect guy to have at the helm for such a mission. He has an amazing workshop in West Berkeley and some interesting thoughts on the intersection of physical and digital creation:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Quotes on Journalism: One Old, One New]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/29/two-quotes-on-journalism/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T17:10:57-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/29/two-quotes-on-journalism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy <a href="http://www.usa.gov/Citizen/Topics/Voting.shtml">Election Day</a>. Below are two quotes on the subject of journalism, one from a great mind of the present, and one from a great mind of the past.</p>

<h4>From the present:</h4>

<blockquote><p>The post-fact literature is built in part on nostalgia for the world before people like Bigfoot showed up in the public sphere, for the days when Newsweek reflected moderately liberal consensus without also providing a platform for orthographically-challenged wingnuts to rant about the President. People who want those days back tell themselves (and anyone else who will listen) that they don’t want to impose their views on anybody. They just want agreement on the facts.
&hellip;
There’s no way to get Cronkite-like consensus without someone like Cronkite, and there’s no way to get someone like Cronkite in a world with an Internet; there will be no more men like him, because there will be no more jobs like his. To assume that this situation can be reversed, and everyone else will voluntarily sign on to the beliefs of some culturally dominant group, is a fantasy. To assume that they should, or at least that they should hold their tongue when they don’t, is Napoleonic in its self-regard. <strong>Yet this is what the people who long for the clarity of the old days are longing for.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p><strong>—Clay Shirky</strong>, Oct. 17th, 2012
from <em><a href="http://www.poynter.org/latest-news/everyday-ethics/191757/shirky-we-are-indeed-less-willing-to-agree-on-what-constitutes-truth/">‘We are indeed less willing to agree on what constitutes truth’</a></em></p>

<h4>From the past:</h4>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I can hardly regret having escaped the appalling waste of time and spirit which would have been involved in reading the war news or taking more than an artificial and formal part in conversations about the war. To read without military knowledge or good maps accounts of fighting which were distorted before they reached the Divisional general and further distorted before they left him and then "written up&rdquo; out of all recognition by jounralists, to strive to master what will be contradicted the next day, to fear and hope intensely on shaky evidence, is surely an ill use of the mind.</p></blockquote>

<p>Even in peacetime <strong>I think those are very wrong who say that schoolboys should be encouraged to read the newspapers. Nearly all that a boy reads there in his teens will be known before he is twenty to have been false in emphasis and interpretation, if not in fact as well, and most of it will have lost all importance. Most of what he remembers he will therefore have to unlearn; and he will probably have acquired a taste for vulgarity and sensationalism</strong> and the fatal habit of fluttering from paragraph to paragraph to learn how an heiress has been divorced in California, a train derailed in France, and quadruplets born in New Zealand."</p>

<p><strong>—CS Lewis</strong>, 1966
from <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Surprised-Joy-Shape-Early-Life/dp/0156870118">Surprised by Joy</a></em></p>

<p>It seems that the clarity of the old days might not have been so clear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
