<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-22T03:20:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Dodds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making it Count: Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2014/01/20/making-it-count-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-20T09:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2014/01/20/making-it-count-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last few weeks I&rsquo;ve had the privilege of rubbing shoulders with a handful of new people on a daily basis. They are students and instructors we&rsquo;ve brought into the fold of the intensive code school I run at work.</p>

<p>My interactions with them have produced the same question enough times for me to think there might be value in answering it comprehensively on this blog. Here&rsquo;s the inquiry:</p>

<blockquote><p>How do you get everything done?</p></blockquote>

<p>Being asked about productivity and work gave me pause for a few reasons. First, we do get a whole lot done at The Iron Yard—more than average, I&rsquo;d say—but I don&rsquo;t generally <em>feel</em> like we&rsquo;re some super-productive anomaly. I feel like we&rsquo;re people who put 110% into work that we love.</p>

<p>Secondly, and more importantly, the question made me think about the non-work aspects of our lives that most people don&rsquo;t see, like family.</p>

<p>Accomplishing a significant amount of anything (and doing it well) requires sacrifice. We are all aware of this from a young age: getting high marks in school means you forgo some amount of play time. This principle of sacrifice and reward follows us for the rest of our lives.</p>

<p>As a result, on some level, when someone asks you how you &ldquo;get everything done,&rdquo; they are asking &ldquo;what are you sacrificing?&rdquo;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to answer that question (for me) over several articles on this blog. Fortunately, there&rsquo;s a whole lot more to it than answering just that one question. Accomplishing great things in life, in work and family, isn&rsquo;t just about sacrifice. I&rsquo;ll cover things I&rsquo;ve learned about time management, sleep, health, process, email, task-management, knowing others well, knowing yourself well and much more.</p>

<p><strong>Why write about these things?</strong></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s been a huge amount written on this subject. Some of the pieces I&rsquo;ve read are akin to entrepreneurial self-therapy through writing. That can be a good thing—writing can force you to really think through things. At the same time, the amount of snake-oil productivity and self-help advice out there is sickening.</p>

<p>For me, figuring this stuff out is extremely important. I&rsquo;ve worked alongside too many people who have given up too much in the name work and looked back in regret. Many people are asking these questions and the answers will be different based on their personality and circumstances.</p>

<p>As I&rsquo;ve grown and made mistakes, people who took the time to share honestly from their experiences have significantly reduced the learning curve for me and steered my feet away from many a pitfall.</p>

<p>As I do the same, hopefully someone following along will reap similar lessons on their journey.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Follow Your Procrastination (Or, How I Changed Careers)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2012/10/14/follow-your-procrastination/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T11:21:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/ericdodds/blog/2012/10/14/follow-your-procrastination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago my friend posted a quote about procrastination:</p>

<blockquote><p>The work you do while you procrastinate is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life. <strong>–Jessica Hische</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>Upon first read the concept was interesting, but it&rsquo;s full weight didn&rsquo;t hit me until much later. I think the delayed reaction was due to my professional youth &ndash; at the time I was earning spurs on my first national brand and consuming knowledge from my veteran boss like a dry sponge. The specificity of the industry (marketing) was far less important to me than the unique opportunities I had to carry more responsibility than normal for my age.</p>

<p>After a good while, though, my rate of absorption began to slow. As a wise man <a href="http://gim.ie/5CIK">once said</a>, &ldquo;<em>in this department of life, as in every other, thrills come at the beginning and do not last.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>While I still thoroughly enjoyed my day-to-day responsibilities, a flattened learning curve afforded me more time to expand my reading and thinking about marketing, business, and more. Interestingly, my curiosity led me mostly towards the internet, technology, and entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>Hacker News and WIRED became regular reads, I began grabbing lunch with startup addicts like <a href="http://doddcaldwell.com">Dodd Caldwell</a>. I even started teaching myself basic HTML.</p>

<p>I also channeled my off-hours energy (and learning) into attempts to start a few companies. I began to scan my day-to-day experiences for annoyances or problems that I thought technology could iron out. At the time, I also happened to live with one of the most talented developers I&rsquo;ve ever met, and he was happy for a few new challenges to tackle.</p>

<p>In about a years' time, we both began and killed a rental payment web app and a wedding website service. (It was awesomely deflating to see Wordpress release a <a href="http://weddings.wordpress.com">phenomenal wedding product</a> not too long after we started writing code.)</p>

<p>Around that same time a friend told me that he heard about an extra volunteer spot at a sold-out conference called <a href="http://grok.cc">GROK</a>. I knew that some of the brightest minds in the country gather there to talk about technology, design, and the internet, so I was thrilled to take him up.</p>

<p>GROK did two very important things for me: First, it fully confirmed my passion for the industry, giving me clear direction for my next career move.</p>

<p>Second, it introduced me to a few gentleman named <a href="http://matthewsmith.cc">Matthew Smith</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/peterbarth">Peter Barth</a>, who would later provide the opportunity for that career move.</p>

<p>In different spheres, both had been forging a foundation of design and technology in the Upstate, Matthew through gathering some of the top talent in the nation and forming <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com">CoWork</a>, and Peter through a startup accelerator called The Next Big Thing.</p>

<p>When our paths crossed at GROK, it just so happens that they were talking about combining forces to form a single organization that shared resources, collaboration, and talent to better position our community as the place for all things tech in the Southeast.</p>

<p>It also just so happens that they needed another team member to manage both execution and promotion of their programs.</p>

<p>At that point, though, the merger was still an idea over lunch. But lunches turned into meetings, and meetings turned into branding work, and <a href="http://theironyard.com">The Iron Yard</a> was born, along with an offer for yours truly.</p>

<p>In November my procrastination will turn into my paycheck, and I couldn&rsquo;t be more excited.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
