<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Introspection | Eric Dodds]]></title>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/categories/introspection/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-19T13:53:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Grown Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/all-grown-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-09T11:35:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/all-grown-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had an updated photo taken for my profile on the Brains on Fire website. My previous shot was over 4 years old, and I thought it would be fun to share both. Please note the electrical tape holding the saddle together in the hippie shot.</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/collage.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/collage.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>_Bonus: me riding a bike through the office at night. _</p>

<p><a href="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/eric-new-night.jpg"><img src="http://ericdodds.com/v2/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/eric-new-night.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Like Working Out, But it Makes Me Better at My Job]]></title>
    <link href="http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/i-dont-like-working-out-but-it-makes-me-better-at-my-job/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T07:41:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ericdodds.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/i-dont-like-working-out-but-it-makes-me-better-at-my-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s get one thing straight: I&rsquo;m a scrawny human being. Weights have never looked favorably on my lanky appendages, and even if they did I&rsquo;d look like a freak with cantaloupe biceps. Despite the physiological cards I&rsquo;ve been dealt, though, I still do strength training three times a week.</p>

<p>Recently my wife pointed out something she (and I) found interesting (we&rsquo;ve been married 5 months so new discoveries abound): I don&rsquo;t have any specific goals for strength training. I&rsquo;m not a fitness junkie, I don&rsquo;t have a need or desire to get super strong, I don&rsquo;t need to lose weight or change the way I look, and the health benefit isn&rsquo;t imperative &ndash; our lifestyle is filled with other aerobic activity several times a week (running, biking, hiking, etc.). So, understandably, she asked why I still train so consistently. Or, more bluntly, why would I put myself through pain when I didn&rsquo;t really need to?</p>

<p>Up until then, my thoughts on the subject hadn&rsquo;t traveled outside my own head, so synthesizing them and communicating them was an interesting exercise. My response went something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>I think I work out because choosing to do something I really don&rsquo;t want to do, something that is consistently difficult and painful to overcome, makes the other battles in work and life easier to face and overcome.</p></blockquote>

<p>In short, the battle of working out develops a fitness in difficulty that pays dividends when other battles happen at work and home.</p>

<p>Sure, I feel good after a workout, but I don&rsquo;t love heaving out pull ups or wincing through lunges. I do think, though, that the discipline of mind in hardship makes me a better employee, boss, and husband.</p>

<p><em>(Well, that and the fact that I can still beat both of my brothers arm wrestling. I&rsquo;ve never beat my dad, but time and age virtually guarantee a win at some point. Yes, that anticipation is clearly horrible and unfair, but family rivalries are family rivalries.)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
